We're going to call it order this regular meeting for a clock at the time of the Miami City Council for today's day.
Item number two, resolution naming the city of Miami and the new city of Miami, animal control facility,
located at 7205D North East.
And if you guys will bear with me, I'm going to read this resolution.
Resolution of the city council of the city of Miami, Oklahoma declaring,
Kich Kahili, animal control facility is the name of the animal control facility in Miami, Oklahoma.
Whereas the late kin catcher and is widely known of the generous supporters of the city of Miami, animal control facility,
and whereas Irene Kahili has been the generous supporter of the local animal welfare society,
and whereas service to the community is indeed the foundation of our city and this country
and the endeavors that can't any of on catcher and Irene Kahili demonstrate commitment
to improving the quality of life for the animal population of Miami.
And whereas the Miami City Council is in agreement with the proposed name of Kich Kahili, animal control facility,
as a fitting and proper name for the city of Miami City, currently under construction at 7205D northeast in Miami.
Now, therefore, be it resolved that mere shorts and the Miami City Council do hereby declare the animal control facility,
located at 7205D northeast to be known as the Kich Kahili, animal control facility.
In witness where I have here on two set my hand and calls the seal of the city of Miami, Oklahoma to be a fixed on this 28th day of June,
in the year of our Lord, 2016.
And I would ask if we had a motion to approve the resolution.
Motion to approve my second.
Second.
We'll call please.
Johnson.
All right.
Lewis.
I'm foraster.
All right.
Western.
Ladies.
Would you come out here?
She didn't call it.
Well, I wanted to get a picture.
Yeah.
We could.
We're going to go on with a couple of consent agenda items if you can call and see she may not be able to be here.
If not, we'll get a picture with Irene.
But I'd like to get involved in here if we can.
Okay.
So we're going to move on to item number three, public input on schedule personal appearance.
There's only one of the audits that wishes to address the council on any of the agenda items.
They're being non item for us in the consent agenda.
Staff is recommending items five through 14 be placed on the consent agenda.
If there are no questions, I would entertain a motion.
Motion to approve my.
And a second.
Second.
Will call.
Johnson.
All right.
Western.
We're going to take out on 15 right quick while we wait to see if we can find the bond.
Grand Armour of the Republic of Cemetery, Mowing Service contract for 16-75 amendment for 16-17.
And can I understand you last time that this agenda item be placed on this meeting, give you a chance to visit with Brian about the question that he thought I'd understand that conversation.
We did today.
So if there are no other questions, I would entertain a motion to approve.
And I'll make that second roll call, please.
Western?
Shult?
Aye.
Forster?
That confused.
Sorry.
Hey, Lewis.
Hi.
Johnson.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I know you were prepared to talk about it.
I just wanted to make a comment that I visited with Kim earlier today.
She answered all my questions and just for clarification purposes.
What I asked them for, and I appreciate her meeting with me today to do that.
Thank you.
Item 16, resolution approving the incurring of a deadness by the Miami Special Utility Authority,
considering to the issuance of certificates of indebtedness, evidenceing the same.
Waving competitive bidding there on and declaring an emergency.
And if you recall last week, Greg Nietzscheu came, shared some information with us on this item,
we postponed voting on it.
We could have voted that night, but we postponed it a week just to give all the council members a chance to review,
asking any questions that they had meeting.
And so this would be the time if you have any.
I know Greg, we didn't ask him to come back.
Dean is certainly here to answer any questions.
This would be a 30-year term.
Although the ban, which are the bond anticipation notes, still have two years before they have to be
redeemed because the rates are so historically low right now.
We think it's in the best interest of the city and the citizens to go ahead and redeem those now.
And so that's what this issue is about.
And there are no questions.
I would have taken a motion to approve the resolution.
Make a motion.
And a second.
The local place.
Forster.
I.
Western.
Johnson.
All right.
Yeah.
You need to vote.
That's a emergency clause.
That.
Yeah.
There's no emergency clause in this series of resolution.
Okay.
And this is really the beginning of the fairly long process.
We'll actually be issuing the bonds in early September.
Okay.
So.
If I were, you missed a reading of the resolution, but you'll certainly get a copy of it.
But would like for you to come forward you and Irene.
And let's take a couple of pictures.
If you don't mind.
Yeah.
And we expect a speech.
We expect a speech, mom.
And she is.
Come on.
Just quick question do we have a completion date, an estimated completion date on that?
Okay, thank you.
Okay, we are going to change things up just a little bit.
We're going to take item number 21 now, which is Executive Session.
For student to 25, OS 307 B1 for the purpose of discussing employment.
Also for student to 25, OS 307 E and 25, OS Section 305.
Going to Executive Session for the reasons listed on agenda I am 21.
Most going to Executive Session.
And a second?
Second.
Bowl call please.
Johnson.
I.
Blueess I. Forster.
High.
Weston.
And we're going to start out with just.
It's not.
He told me a little bit that I'm still in the second one of you saying.
Okay.
What's this?
There we go.
Okay, we are out of Executive Session.
And four or 52.
We're going to jump back up now to item 17.
Discussion and City Charter.
I know you've done a lot of.
Preparatory work.
Unfortunately, we're going to feel well.
And so we're not going to take up this discussion tonight.
Just a minute.
We're going to take no action on that item for now.
Item 18 is other new business.
Dean or anyone any new business?
Not for me.
Okay.
Item 19 mayor and council committee announcements.
Any announcements?
I want to thank Tyler Klein of money.
I guess the city had a phase problem and one of the grids need to find it.
He gave me a phone call.
Thermal Fisher and we were able to shut down.
A lot of our processes that were critical to maintain the power load.
Thank you.
It saved us a lot.
money and a lot of time. It's ironic that I also want to say on behalf of Jane and Farms,
we had a transformer go down and about a third of our growing operation took a hit and I
made a phone call in Tyler and he had crews tied up with a GDRDA and they broke free and came out
and within two hours had a transformer replaced and I know everybody had Jane and especially
myself was happy to get back up and run it so thank you for that Tyler. Tyler I think what
last two weeks you've replaced about seven or eight transformers throughout the town and just trying to
keep up with everything and also what we're talking about with GDRDA getting into our transformers
and making sure they're properly maintained so he has crews doing a great job like great. Thank you.
Okay any other announcements? They're being known. I'm 20 today manager Dean. The only thing is
is getting ready for 4th July. I think the last meeting last week we talked about
regulations on firework so it's put everything on our webpage and I want to think the
news record for having a good article about that too and we just hope everybody has a safe and
happy 4th July. And dry. And dry. What is not such a bad thing with firework?
True.
Well I hadn't planned on bringing that up but we have we have put on the website and also the news record
the schedule of road closures for the Turnpike Gate as well. The Oklahoma Turnpike Authority
has given us that information and I think they modified the reader board. I noticed that yesterday
where it's flashing much quicker talking about when the on-ramps and off-ramps will be closed.
So what are the alternatives when they're closed? The alternatives are you either if it's closed now
it's starting I think it starts at about 7 p.m. and goes to about 5 a.m. So during the day it shouldn't be
a but you'll probably have to either go to Athens or just if you know it's going to be closed
takes 69. I know I appreciate that email because I've actually been in farms in their trucks
and as well as everybody else through town trying to get on the turnpike Gate. It looks to me
life you're trying to do it as quickly as possible if they can completely close it and whether
permits they can probably get it done fairly quickly. Okay. We've already done item 21 so item and I'm just
reminded but we still have another meeting after that and so don't go anywhere. Item 22 for the
City Council agenda is adjourned if we have a motion to adjourn. Motion to adjourn. And a second please.
Second roll call. Forster. My question. I wish I. Johnson. All right. So. All right. Thank you.